<ecclesiacrm>
<name>8.0.0</name>
<created_at>2017-12-25T20:27:02Z</created_at>
<published_at>2017-12-26T09:15:32Z</published_at>
<assets>
    <asset>
          <name>EcclesiaCRM-8.0.0.zip</name>
          <browser_download_url>https://www.ecclesiacrm.com/download/EcclesiaCRM-8.0.0.zip</browser_download_url>
          <size>78216999</size>
          <created_at>2026-04-03T 7h00Z</created_at>
          <updated_at>2026-04-03T 7h01Z</updated_at>
    </asset>
</assets>
<body>New version 8.0.0

- new main dashboard : everything is rewritten with plugins and is managed with drag and drop (persons, families, to do list, etc ...) 
- the CRM is now rewritten for plugins (not only with the dashboard).
- Jitsi is now a plugin : install, upgrade ... and is available for 8x8 with an api key
- Full 2FA authentication support with otp key
- CALDAV : full calendar update + optimizations
- CARDDAV : addressbok server is now fully working
- WEBDAV : brand new edrive view
    - it is now possible to share files and folders, to other users
    - PDF, DOCX, XLSX preview is supported now
- Now you can send your confirmation datas with a nice backend (with authentication) and pending/done status
    - new ident route : for people verifications (persons and families)
    - the verification process is completely rewriten too : confirm reports
- Volunteer management has been completely rewritten to differentiate between participants in a group within the CRM.
- Meta search engine enhancement (automatic search completion).
- an admin can now take the control of another account
- New role : "Manage resource reservation schedules (room, computer, projectors)"
- It is possible to create hierarchies for volunteers and administrators by volunteer opportunity and to rank them by color and type.
- pastoral care person/family new views (more informations : groups etc ...)
- pastoral care filter enhancements.
- New event list view (full dynamic) in js.
- PhotoUpload is rewritten to work with modernized browsers and can now manage all the devices.
- Event calendar update : full resource management (for room, video and computers).
- TextEditor : font customization (through the systemsettings)
- kiosk checkin/checkout is rewritten
- App integrety enhancement (global verifications for the CRM and for the plugins)
    - Full System informations
- family/person view optimizations
- person View
    - optimizations
    - personview update for group
    - PersonView.php + privacy messages
- family view + privacy messages
- print view is rewritten for person view and family view.
- Family and Person pastoral care enhancements graphic upgrade
- mailchimp
    - GUI update (manage list is now completely rewritten)
    - mailchimp is now full RGPD (for the email addresses).
    - mailchimp can manage different fonts and can be customized
    - mailchimp (now for a campaign the sender name is now the crm name)
    - Person Mailchimp activation and de-activation
    - can communicate with mail plugin (loke sendinblue plugin)
- word export is now fully supported
- Event Editor : free attendees enhancements.
- Sunday School View charts updates (for the months)
- qrcode checkout enhancements
- drag and drop improvements
- Family model : coordinates update automatically
- search api now use the new font awesome
- Sunday school pdf export enhancements (free attendees are now included).
- badges are completely rewriten too (with previews through Imagick)
- pdf badges qrcode enhancements
- pdf badge preview (in sundayschool and group)
- SystemSettings.php : enhancements bootstrap dialog
- UserEditor is rewritten to be in categories and plugins is added
- New Personal settings
- Calendar sidebar enhancements for chrome
- GroupView GUI update
- person editor now manage the birthday with an unique textfield.
- People attendees enhancements (checkin process).
- file manager refactor and upload window enhancements, new icons too.
- Query view enhancement completely rewritten in v2
- trees are now included in each views
- the login logout is completely rewritten
- jwt is now with header token rewritten
- Fullscreen button enhancement
- GroupView is completely rewritten
- signature improvements.
- cache settings for v2 arch to accelerate experience
- All the sidebar is completely rewritten (GUI)
- 31 languages are now supported
- php 8.1 is now the lowest version and php 8.5 is completely supported
- etc ...


Bugs correction

- DatePicker show the popup now at the right place.
- Mailchimp service is rewritten for the latest mailchimp api.
- GroupService bug resolution
- pastoralcaredashboard.php bug resolution
- systemdbupdate callout
- People controllers minor bug res
- PersonSearchRes.php : bug resolution
- Boostraper : minor bug resolution
- CalendarEventV2Controller : bug correction
- skin/js/Footer.js : select2 jquery bug resolution (in some case select2 isn't select by default).
- mysql install.sql : bug resolution gdpr
- Include/Footer.php : upgrade title bug resolution
- EcclesiaCRM/Search/PersonSearchRes.php : rgpd bug resolution
- EcclesiaCRM/Reports/PDF_RealAttendance.php : bug correction with date
- EcclesiaCRM/dto/Photo.php : php 8 bug resolution
- skin/js/system/setup.js : xdebug correction
- familyview add pdf report bug crmjsom
- xss/sql injection bug corrections
- security update (with jwt enhancements)
- photouploader is now working properly
- etc ...

Inner Beauty
- no more php code everything is rewritten in v2
- fetch is now at the place of ajax. Goal : no more jquery and speed enhancements
- popover is now activated
- Docker dev env
- propel beta3
- all the code is now v2 stage, no more legacy code
- App integrety upgrade for imagick
- New JWT strategy per user and ONLY HTTPS web site are now supported
- propel update to latest
- optimization with js code propel and jwt
- optimization with
   - list events
   - dashboard
   - calendar
   - mailchimp
- font awesome is now in the latest version
- new ChurchInfoReportTCPDF.php for uTF8 fonts.
- All code is rewritten for 31 languages
- CSV_RealAttendance.php
- full support of tcpdf for chinese, japan, etc ... fonts.
- PDF_AddressReport.php
- PDF_Attendance.php
- PDF_Badge.php
- PDF_CanvassBriefingReport.php
- PDF_CertificatesReport.php
- PDF_ComfirmReport_EMAIL.php
- PDF_DepositReport.php
- PDF_Directory.php
- PDF_GroupDirectory.php
- PDF_Label.php
- PDF_NewsletterLabels.php
- PDF_RealAttendance.php
- PDF_ZeroGivers.php
- PDF_ComfirmReport_EMAIL.php new class
- support of all currencies in 31 languages.
- refactor of runquery strategy
- USISTAddress deleted
- IE 11 is no more supported

* CSVCreateFile.php : no more RunQuery
* EventAttendance.php : no more RunQuery
etc ....

Inner Coherence

See full changelog here</body>
</ecclesiacrm>
